Okay, so I asked you to search for textview android.
Evet, sizden 'textview android' ile ilgili arama yapmanızı istedim.
Usually, when I do a search, I always add the word android at the end of it,
Genelde arama yapaken, daima sonuna android kelimesini eklerim,
so that it only shows me android results.
böylece sadece android sonuçları ekrana gelir.
The first link is for TextView, and it's on developer.android.com site so
İlk bağlantı TextView ile ilgili ve developer.android.com adresinde.
I'm going to click on it.
Ona tıklıyorum.
I can ignore most of the information on this page except
Bu sayfadaki birçok bilgiyi görmezden gelebilirim
I can read the class overview but the most important thing is down here,
Tüm sınıf açıklamasını okuyabilirim fakat en önemli kısım aşağıda:
the XML attributes.
XML öznitelikleri.
So I can manually scroll the list, but that will literally take forever.
El ile listeyi aşağı kaydırabilirim, ama bunun sonu gelmeyecektir.
So, I'm going to use the fine feature that I talked about earlier.
O yüzden, daha önce konuştuğumuz bul özelliğini kullanacağım.
The quiz question was about finding an attribute that would change the text to
Test sorusu yazıyı kalın veya italik yapacak özniteliği bulmakla alakalıydı.
So I'm going to search for the word bold.
O yüzden kalın kelimesini arayacağım.
Cool, so let's look at this description.
Harika, şu tanıma bakalım.
It says Style (bold, italic, bolditalic) for the text.
Diyor ki, metin için stil (kalın, italik, kalın italik).
That sounds pretty good, so I can click on this attribute.
Kulağa iyi geliyor, buna tıklıyorum.
For android:textStyle, it seems that the different values are normal, bold,
Android:textStyle için, farklı değerler
Let's try it out.
Hadi deneyelim.
The documentation says that if I add android:textStyle attribute,
Dokümentasyon diyor ki, eğer android:textStyle özniteliğini eklersem,
then I can set it to be bold, italic, or normal.
onu kalın, italik veya normal olacak şekilde ayarlayabilirim.
So let's try bold.
Kalını deneyelim.
Nice, and it bolds the font.
Güzel, font kalınlaştı.
And let's be adventurous and try italic as well.
Macera olsun diye italik deneyelim.
Awesome, it italicizes the text.
Müthiş, metin italik oldu.
So this was an example of how you can look at documentation
İşte TextView ayarları için gerekli öznitelikleri
to find new attributes that you can set on your TextView.
nasıl bulabileceğinizle ilgili bir örnek.
In the future, when you're working on something and you get stuck, or
Gelecekte, bir şey üzerinde çalışırken sıkışırsanız veya
you don't know how to do it,
nasıl yapacağını bilmiyorsanız,
remember they can always use documentation as a resource.
dokümantasyonu kaynak olarak kullanabileceğinizi unutmayın.